# **Siming Yang**

9329 University Crescent Burnaby, BC, V5A 4Y4

(604) 537-8662, Yang.Siming@Outlook.com, https://github.com/YangSiming99

# Summary

A motivated and passionate web application developer with 2+ years of experience building and deploying web applications created using a combination of NodeJS, HTML, CSS, Javascript, React, and PostgreSQL. Was responsible for developing features in NodeJS, designing HTML and CSS pages, troubleshooting bugs, and writing documentation for a web application in my current role.

# **Experience**

# **Web App Developer (Internship)** - Hillside Wealth Management

APRIL 2019 - PRESENT

- Developed a web application that automates the process of recording and displaying of financial data, decreasing the original time requirement by over 200%
- Formatted JSON data to be sent between the client and server using AJAX and POST requests
- Implemented new features and pages using Javascript, HTML, and CSS
- Backend functions created using NodeJS and a PostgreSQL database
- Created unit tests using Jest

#### Retail Cashier - SuperStore

JUNE 2018 - SEPTEMBER 2018

- Provided Exceptional Customer Service
- Accurately entering orders into a Point of Sale system and processing Payments
- Maintained Knowledge of advertised specials, weekly ads, and other promotions

#### Education

## Computer Information Technology Diploma - BCIT, Vancouver

SEPTEMBER 2017 - APRIL 2019

# **Relevant Coursework**

#### Hillside Wealth Autostocks Project (ACIT 4900) - BCIT, Vancouver

**JANUARY 2019 - APRIL 2019** 

- Developed a web application that automates the process of recording financial information using Agile
- Web application written in HTML5, CSS, NodeJS, Express, and Jquery
- Formatted JSON data to be sent between the client and the server
- Version control done through Github

## **Developing Web Applications (ACIT 2520)** - BCIT, Vancouver

**JANUARY 2018 - APRIL 2018** 

- Experience creating interactive web applications using Javascript NPM, NodeJS, and Express
- Asynchronous javascript achieved using Promises and Callbacks
- Requested and displayed JSON data from external API's

## Web & Mobile App Development (ACIT 3650) - BCIT, Vancouver

SEPTEMBER 2018 - DECEMBER 2018

- Created IOS and Android Compatible applications using Javascript and React-Native
- Developed Animated Applications using NPM and React animation Libraries
- Created Reusable React Components that could be used for future projects

# **Technical Proficiencies**

### **Technologies**

HTML, CSS, Bootstrap 4, Javascript ES6, Jquery, NodeJS, Express, React, React-Native, MySQL, PostgreSQL, JSON, Python

# **Operating Systems**

Windows Vista, 7, 8, 10, Server 2016, CentOS, Ubuntu, Fedora

#### Network

DNS, DHCP, LAN, WAN, SSH, SFTP, HTTP, HTTPS

#### Other

Microsoft Office Suite, Visual Studio Code, Chrome/Firefox/Edge, Search Engines